Wrege, Charles D. Collection of History of Management Photographs 6014 P
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Charles D. Wrege Collection of History of Management Photographs
1879- 1996
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Wrege, Charles D.
6014 P
2.33 cubic feet
2.3 linear ft.
Photographs.
8232912
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, October 31, 2012
EAD encoding:
Randall Miles, October 30, 2015
Biographical / Historical
Charles "Chuck" Wrege finished his undergraduate degree in Upsala College, obtained his Masters degree at the New School fo Social Research and another Masters of Business Administration and his Ph.D. at NYU. He taught industrial management at Rutgers University for 30 years. He became a renowned historian, researcher and writer. He is regarded as a "National Treasure" by many in his field because of his expertise and the seminal research he has done in the area of management history.
Scope and Contents
Factory inventory, manufacturing, and improvement for various companies including Hawthorne Works, Manufacturing Investment Company and Madison Paper company; owner and employee portraits; advertisement for improved lighting, product assembly and testing over more than a century.
Photographer of many images was likely Marty Labno, according to Dr. Wrege.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5167: Charles D. Wrege Hawthorne Studies Research Data 5618: Charles D. Wrege Research Papers Regarding History of Management 5618 P: Charles D. Wrege History of Management Collection of Midvale Steel Company Photographs 6012: Charles D. Wrege Papers 6012m: Charles D. Wrege "Facts and Fallacies of Hawthorne" Doctoral Dissertation. 1961 6012 AV: Charles D. Wrege Collection of Audio-Visual Materials 6013 P: Charles D. Wrege Collection of Midvale Steel Company Photographic Negatives 6014: Charles D. Wrege Collection of History of Management Documents 6014 P: Charles D. Wrege Collection of History of Management Photographs 6054: Charles D. Wrege Collection of Additional Taylor Charts 6118 AV: Kheel Center AV Collection 6271: Charles D. Wrege Collection of International Management Institute Correspondence 6304: Charles Wrege Collection of Midvale Steel Company Index Cards
8232912
- Photographs of 1926 advertisements on industrial lighting - copies of originals (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Coil Box photo in Relay Test Room (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Original photo of Coilwinding Test Room at Hawthorne in the 1926-1927 tests (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Marty Lano's 1981 photo original of Building 47-5, Site of Relay Test Room 8 1926-1927 Illuminated Tests plus sketch (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Scope and Contents
  July 27, 1981
- Permalloy loading coil (photo #133524), 1925 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  February 21 1925
- 1926-1927 Light test room at the Hawthorne. 1926 photo #142902 (Benday screen for publishing) (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Sorting jack springs in Inspection Department Hawthorne, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Inspection Department at Hawthorne. Original photo #133675 - night view - from Snow 1924-1925 Report (Box 1, Folder 8)
  March 6, 1925
- Original Photograph of E-type relay 1925 - photo #131677 from Snow 1924-1925 Report (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Enlargement of Order Section of Relay Assembly Department (position 135676), 1925 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Originals Assembly E-type relay. Relay Assembly Department. 1925 photo #131671 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Original photo of Relay Assembly Test Room at Hawthorne (from Snow 1924-1925 Report) (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Original photo of #46 Induction Coil at Hawthorne, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  February 12 1925
- Color photograph of Hawthorne Works of Western Electric Company, Chicago, Illinois, 1979 - original (Box 1, Folder 14)
- 35 millimeter slides of Hawthorne Studies Individuals - From Ron Greenwood - originals (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Original photo of Light Test Room at Hawthorne for 1926-1927 Tests - from Snow report of 1926-1927 tests (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Photograph of Charles E. Snow original from Western Electric Personnel Files (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Photograph of converted MorkRvm - Kleinschmidt recorder in Test Room. Original Photo (negatives at Western electric now missing - cdw 8/10/96), 1996 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  August 10, 1996
- Original photo of Homer Hibargen - creator of Riley Assembly Test Room at Hawthorne (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Photograph Coil Winding Department 1925 Original from Snow 1924-1925 Report Photo #135682 3-6-25 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- Early photo of Willimantic Company Linen Company Electric Light Installation 2/14/79, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  February 14, 1979
- 35 millimeter slides of Hawthorne and Joseph and Feiss Company (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Photos from Presentation (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Negative and print of Doctor Isaac Adams House (with his 1882 Glassbrick Basement Windows) Annisquam, Massachusetts (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Daniel Drawbaugh Telephone Photo (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Original photograph of William Daniel Basley (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Photos of Dolphine Jute Mills (Paterson, New Jersey), 1990 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Gilbreth Medical Photos (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Original 1929 photo of Richard A. Feiss from Mrs. Feiss (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Negative of Feiss and Hawthorne (lined screen) (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Original photograph and negative of Maunsel White (save for High Speed Steel) (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Photos of machines High Falls, New York (from original Sanford Thompson files) (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Photo of Mary Jassett in office - circa 1915; Bendary screen for N-file May 23, 1979, 1915-1979 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Original photos of Doctor Jordon Ball, early Industrial Psychiatrist - 1916-1922 (includes photo of his associate chief August Vollmer of Berkeley Police Department 1918) (Box 2, Folder 12)
- 35 millimeter slides of Mrs. Pattinson's Experimental Housekeeping Station (Colonia, New Jersey) (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Management History Photos (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Original photograph of F.W. Taylor from Mrs. Richard A. Feiss (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Passaic Metal Ware photos - copies of originals 1989 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Copies of original photos of Henry Noll, House in Bethlehem, Pennsylvania and Noll and wife plus R. Feiss Clothcraft Shops operators playing ball (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Original tintype of Henry Noll, 1899 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Flood at Madison, Maine (Manufacturing Investment Company), 1936 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  April 19, 1936 - original photos
- Two photographs of construction of Manufacturing Investment Company - Madison, Maine - 1889. #1 Digesters #2 Main Building - originals (Box 2, Folder 20)
- 1889 Photograph of building of the Madison Mill of the Manufacturing Investment Company. Madison, Maine. (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Madison Main Manufacturing Investment, 1890 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  January 28, 1890
- 1936 flood photos of Madison Paper Company. 1982 photos of Madison Paper Company, 1936-1982 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Gilbreth photos from Richard Walp Countyway Medical Library, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  August 28, 1985
- Illustrations (photos) for Canal Museum paper on Taylor at Midvale (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Manufacturing Investment company photos, 1891-1899 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  November 1899, February 25 1891
- Color slides and negatives of Henry Noll Site of his house and concrete houses in Bethlehem, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Original photos of Manufacturing Investment Company, Madison, Maine, plus 1982 photos (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Photo of Horace King Hathaway plus copy negative Taylor (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Harlow S. Person (Box 2, Folder 30)
- Keppele Hall - employed by Richard A. Feiss at the Joseph and Feiss Company (Box 2, Folder 31)
- "Charles Day. A Memory" by his wife Margaret Dunning Day Philadelphia, 1934., 1879-1931 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  Copy #12 of a limited edition 25 copies. Signed by the author. Contains original photographs; binder includes the dates 1879-1931
- History of Management Photographs - 5/2010 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  photo-copies of photographs
- Sprague Electric Motor (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Mary Hennan/Richard A. Feiss Photos (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Hawthorne Photo Album, 1925 (Box 5)
  - Hawthorne Photo Album, 1925 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Hawthorne Photo Album, 1925 (Box 6)
  - Hawthorne Photo Album, 1925 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Hawthorne Photo Album, 1925 (Box 7)
  - Hawthorne Photo Album, 1925 (Box 7, Folder 1)